CURRICULUM VITAE

DR. RER. NAT. MARTIN BIES

Personal Details

Address: Université libre Bruxelles

Campus Plaine, Builling NO, Office O.6.111

Email: Martin.Bies@ulb.ac.be

Nationality: German
Date of birth: 15/12/1987



SUMMARY

Education PhD in Physics (Heidelberg university – defended on 01/02/2018)

Past research String theory – development of mathematical software (via GitHub

and including machine learning) and computation of massless spectra

Teaching experience Tutor for 8 lecture courses (since Oct. 2012)

Senior Tutor in 2016 and 2018

Language skills German – mother tongue

English – fluent (Imperial College International Diploma)

French – Basic knowledge

Scholarships Studienstiftung des deutschen Volkes (Jan. 2010 – Feb. 2018)

FWA – Foundation Wiener-Anspach (since Oct. 2018)

Professional Experience

Since Oct. 2018 Postdoctoral Researcher

Physique Théorique et Mathématique, Université Libre de Bruxelles

Feb. 2018 – Sept. 2018 – Postdoctoral Researcher

Institut für theoretische Physik, Ruprecht-Karls-Universität Heidelberg

EDUCATION

Mar. 2014 – Feb. 2018 PhD studies in physics (Heidelberg university) on the subject

Cohomologies of coherent sheaves and massless spectra in F-theory Supervisor physics: Prof. Dr. Timo Weigand (Uni. Heidelberg) Supervisor mathematics: Prof. Dr. Mohamed Barakat (Uni. Siegen)

Result: Magna cum laude (very good)

Sept. 2012 – Feb. 2014 Master studies in physics (Heidelberg university) on the subject

Cohomologies of holomorphic line bundles in smooth and compact nor-

mal toric varieties

Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Timo Weigand

Result: 1.0

Oct. 2008 – Aug. 2012 Bachelor studies in physics (Heidelberg university) on the subject

Intersecting D6-brane models on $T^2 \times T^2 \times T^2/(\sigma \times \Omega)$ and $T^2 \times T^2 \times T^2$

 $T^2/(\mathbb{Z}_2 \times \mathbb{Z}_2 \times \sigma \times \Omega)$ orientifolds Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Timo Weigand

Result: 1.1

Oct. 2010 – June 2011 Studies abroad at Imperial College (London, United Kingdom)

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

As part of the *homalg_project* of the mathematician *Mohamed Barakat* (Siegen university), I maintain the following *GAP*-packages on my *GitHub*-site https://github.com/HereAround:

- $\bullet \ \ CAP Category Of Projective Graded Modules$
- CAPPresentationCategory
- PresentationsByProjectiveGradedModules
- $\bullet \ \ Truncations Of Presentations By Projective Graded Modules$
- SheafCohomologyOnToricVarieties

SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS

- Cohomologies of coherent sheaves and massless spectra in F-theory (arXiv-ID: 1802.08860)
- Algebraic Cycles and Local Anomalies in F-theory (arXiv-ID: 1706.08528) Collaborators: Christoph Mayrhofer and Timo Weigand
- Gauge Backgrounds and Zero-Mode Counting in F-theory (arXiv-ID: 1706.04616) Collaborators: Christoph Mayrhofer and Timo Weigand
- Chow groups, Deligne cohomology and massless matter in F-theory (arXiv-ID: 1402.5144) Collaborators: Christoph Mayrhofer, Christian Pehle and Timo Weigand

Conferences

Aug. 2018	CAP_days 2018 (Siegen, Germany)
May 2018	Kontaktseminar – Schwerpunkt Banken und Beratung (Bonn, Germany)
May 2018	Physiker im Beruf (Bad Honnef, Germany)
Mar. 2018	string_data 2018 (Munich, Germany)
Jul. 2017	String Pheno 2017 (Virginia, USA)
Dec. 2015	String Math (Sanya, China)
Sept. 2015	Third GAP Days (Trondheim, Norway)
Mar. 2015	Second GAP Days (Aachen, Germany)
Feb. 2015	Physics and Geometry of F-theory (Munich, Germany)
Dec. 2014	Homological Perturbation Theory (Galway, Ireland)
Aug. 2014	GAP Days (Aachen, Germany)
Feb. 2014	Geometry and Physics of String Compactifications (Heidelberg, Germany)

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Apr. 2018 – Oct. 2018	Senior tutor	methods of mathematical physics 1
Oct. $2016 - Mar. 2017$	Tutor	theoretical physics I
Apr. $2016 - Sept. 2016$	Senior tutor	General relativity
Apr. $2015 - Sept. 2015$	Tutor	theoretical physics IV
Oct. $2014 - Mar. 2015$	Tutor	Quantum field theory
Oct. $2013 - Mar. 2014$	Tutor	theoretical physics III
Apr. $2013 - Sept. 2013$	Tutor	theoretical physics II
Oct. $2012 - Mar. 2013$	Tutor	theoretical physics I

${\tt Engagement \ at \ } \textit{Studienstiftung \ des \ deutschen \ Volkes}$

June 2018	Member of the admission board <i>Heidelberg</i>
Dec. 2017	Member of the admission board Ellwangen III
May 2017	Training for admission board members – successfully completed
Nov. 2016	Member of the admission board <i>Heidelberg</i>